What do you think of the car?
Smooth as butter.
Just like my wife.
You are too much sir.
Just like your wife.
How soon will it be ready?
It's a precision job.
The engine is great.
It will take 10-12 days.
Deliver it at my house when it's ready.
- Okay.
Well, the steering is fine.
Not to worry.
That's what I feel.
The roads here are quite shitty.
Of course boss, this car isn't
made for here.
Japan has fantastic roads.
Better than in America?
- Absolutely. Better than America.
Want a cigarette?
-Yes, definitely.
Thank you.
Why is this still here?
It doesn't even work. - Fix it.
Sure thing.
What's that sound?
- What sound?
Listen.
- I can't hear anything.
I think there's a problem with
the differential.
I'll check it in the garage.
- Sure. - Okay.
I'll check it out.
How dare that stupid Fiat
try to overtake me?
Watch out, hero.
What a strange mechanic!
Hi, Mr. Braganza.
- Hello, Albert.
Is the car giving you trouble?
- No, with you around,
what trouble will it give?
Is your Mercedes doing fine?
- Yes, it is.
How's everyone at home?
-fine.
And how is Stella?
- She is fine.
And Dominic?
That problem of yours..
- It has been solved. Thanks a lot.
I see. Go ahead.
I'm waiting for the bill.
Okay, Mr. Braganza. Bye.
- Bye.
Buddy, bring me
a cup of special tea quickly.
fast, fast.
Albert, your girlfriend had called.
When?
- About 15 minutes back.
She said she can't meet you this
evening. She has to attend a party.
Must be a dance party.
why do you care?
I gave him the message na.
Has this milk split?
what's this Seth (business owner)?
The milk in my tea is okay.
Something's wrong with his.
Albert, what will you do
this evening?
Don't charge me for this tea!
- Albert, what will you do this evening?
Albert!
I will think about it.
I am not an alcoholic like you.
Every evening with
mosambi (country liquor).
Rascal!
Buddy, pick up the chair.
Move, move!
Can't you see the car?
Why are you getting
involved in all of this?
Please stay away from all of this.
How can I stay away? I have to do
whatever the union decides.
And is it that
we are demanding too much?
Are we asking for millions, or
a bungalow, or a car?
We demand a respectful life. that's it.
- Damn the strike!
Will being on strike
give you respect?
Forget about the strike. Mom,
will I get tea? - Yes, right away.
Let me pack his lunch.
He'll get late for work.
Try to understand.
There is so much Inflation.
Shouldn't our salaries
also increase accordingly?
Handsome salary and yearly bonus.
Can't we get that? - Yes, you can.
But that's the union's job.
Let them ask,
why are you getting into it?
What if the mill shuts down?
Why would it?
We haven't threatened them.
Moreover, we have..
- This happens all the time.
Your demands will never get met.
Then you'll strike work.
The mill will be closed.
I tell you the union
won't do anything.
Mom, let him at least complete the point.
- What's the point?
Mom is absolutely right.
Calling for strike
is the work of crazy people.
We aren't like them.
We are better off than them.
Have your tea.
- Look at me.
There was a strike at the garage.
I stayed away from it.
I had nothing to do with it.
I do my job, I get my salary.
I'm the only mechanic in Mumbai who
delivers the car to the customer's house.
I get to drive the car.
I am acquainted with
several millionaires.
I don't address them formally.
I don't have to.
I call them by their first names.
Vivek, Murad, their first names.
Like that.
Really Albert, you are
such a fool.
What did you say?
- Fool.
You are the bane of my life.
You and Dominic.
Mom, I spoke to Vivek
about a job for Dominic.
He promised he would look in to it.
Where is Dominic? Where is he?
- Who knows?
Aye, Dominic!
Salaam Javed.
- Hi, Stella.
How are you, Stella?
- Fine.
Albert is in the office.
Thank you, Madhu.
Hello Albert.
Why didn't you answer my call?
I was under the car.
I have good news. I got a promotion.
- I see.
I'm a secretary to the boss now.
- When did the party get over?
Are you talking about the other night?
- Yes.
At about 11:30 pm.
How did you reach home?
Arvind dropped me.
Did you have fun? Did you?
What fun?
All parties are similar.
Albert, I can't refuse
to attend the party.
What would you do in my place?
-Did I stop you?
why are you getting angry
unnecessarily?
Okay tell me, what time
this evening?
I have loads of work.
And tomorrow?
Tomorrow also there's work.
Will you let me know?
This is done.
I'll call you if I get time.
Okay?
Have you had lunch?
- Not yet.
Can I have lunch here?
- Yes, sure.
Go ahead. Have I stopped you?
Now a days there are
more meetings, less work, eh?
Darn him.
Please keep it away son,
you know Albert doesn't like it.
"Okay, Albert doesn't like it."
"Doesn't like this,
Doesn't like that"
"You don't like anything I do."
"This belongs to Albert.
That belongs to Joan."
"Shall I help you?
Shall I sing a song?"
"Shall I help you?"
- You're mad.
Nuts
-Nuts?
"Dominic is nuts."
So what? Who cares?
This world isn't for me.
"This world isn't for me."
"This world belongs to
working men, famous men."
That is right.
You make fun of others
because you are jobless.
See Joan, she also works.
At least she does something.
"Joan! Nuts."
"Dominic is nuts.
He is nuts."
He is nuts ."
I like the colour of your Saree.
Is there anything in that colour?
Red? Let me check.
Your taste is classy.
This is the color I want,
but the design isn't good.
The sari is for my sister.
It's her birthday today.
Will you choose one for her?
You look so much like my sister.
In fact you look better.
See, this sari would be
good for your sister.
Great! That's the color I wanted.
Will you do me another favor?
What?
It's a small request.
Will you wear the sari for me?
I want to know how beautiful
my sister would look.
I will wear it.
I'm like your sister, right?
And your sister is like me.
Just like me?
Is she lame like me too?
Isn't she very pretty?
Is she also handicapped?
Just five more minutes, Albert.
This is the last letter.
Yeah, that's alright.
Well, forget it.
I'll complete it tomorrow.
"Let our flag always fly high."
Bombay.
Where is Europe?
Where are we going this evening?
London or Paris?
Bombay is the best.
Right? Our Bombay is best.
Stella, why are you still here?
I make you work too hard.
I'll take you out for a movie today.
If you refuse, I'll carry you out.
No. Arvind...
I can't come.
why?
This is Albert.
Albert... Arvind.
So, you are the Albert.
I have heard a lot about you.
- I have also...
You should have told me earlier.
We'll see the film some other day.
Let's go Albert.
Stella.
When will you treat me with Goan food?
-After your trip to Singapore.
Bye-bye.
- Okay.
What did I do?
You don't understand..
I cannot refuse to go.
What would you do in my place?
Stella, what would you do in my place?
Tell me that!
I won't tolerate it.
He talks rubbish.
You can travel to Hong Kong and
Singapore with him.
You get me wrong, Albert.
I swear Arvind has never
misbehaved with me.
He might not have.
But I know his type. All rascals.
What can I do if someone
wants to take me to the movies?
He's no ordinary man.
He's Arvind sir, Arvind Sir.
He's rich. He's a businessman.
Had I not been there, you would
have definitely gone with him.
Albert would be toiling
there in the garage.
You would've called and
told me you can't come.
Don't lie Albert,
has it ever happened..
..that I promised to come with you,
but went away with him?
It was his idea to go
for a movie, not mine.
So, you should have gone with him.
Why didn't you?
In anger, you even stop thinking.
Will you even listen to me?
He asked me out for a movie. I didn't.
- Yes, he asked you out.
Why did he ask you? Why didn't he
ask me or others? Mind your dress.
It's blowing away. I told you
to wear a sari. But you never listen.
The men on the streets are staring
at you. - You are crazy.
I wear these dresses because
I like them. Not for others.
You have a response to everything
Albert says.
What happens to you
in Arvind's presence?
Why were you shut then?
Stop it. I can't listen to this.
- You have to. You have to listen to me.
Truth is always bitter.
Don't cover your legs.
Why did you wear a skirt?
Let it fly.
Have a look at my girlfriend's legs.
Constable, you too look.
Darn it! Let it fly off.
I want to go home.
Stella is back.
- Yes.
Fill the form.
She will get it typed tomorrow.
My God! I forgot a certificate.
- What?
Certificate.
-For god's sake you forgot the certificate?
You are great. You think going
to Canada is just like that?
You don't understand.
How can you forget a certificate?
Don't panic, dad.
- Panic? What panic?
I'll get it done.
- All right.
What's wrong, Stella?
I'll go fill the form quickly
and give it to Stella.
What's wrong, Stella? Did you get
into a fight with Albert again?
Alice, how do I look in these clothes?
- You look very beautiful.
Really?
- Yes, you look very beautiful.
Can I borrow Rs. 10?
I'll return it tomorrow.
No need.
Is my money bastardised?
Joan, are you ashamed
that I am your brother?
How does it matter
where I get the money from?
Every person steals
in some way or other.
They steal for a living.
I say upfront that I steal.
Everyone is trapped in their own traps.
I am the only free person.
You are ashamed
to call me your brother?
What exactly are you implying?
Father, I tried very hard.
I did everything,
but he doesn't listen.
What else do I do?
Father, I'm very troubled
about Dominic.
What do I say to him?
How do I reform him?
He has gone astray.
Father, what do I do?
Don't worry. Have faith in God.
He has given life.
He will show him the way.
Father, I am tired.
He laughs at us.
He says we don't understand the world.
Father you say that God has made this
world for good people.
You have to take efforts to become
a good person. But he makes fun of it.
God moves in mysterious ways.
You need to accept things
as they are.
I know Dominic well.
He is a good person.
Send him over to me.
How do I do that?
I tried a lot,
but he doesn't listen to me.
Have faith in God. Pray that He will
put sense into him and save him.
Yes, father.
Everything is in God's hand.
Please don't worry, my child.
Okay.
Everything is in God's hand.
Uncle, you've got solid capacity.
Before you take my daughter away,
you should have a small peg.
No, uncle. Too much alcohol
will drive me crazy.
Uncle, the movie..
That's enough. Last drink.
Drink it up, Albert.
One can't predict the future.
Which car have you brought?
- Duke.
Foreign car. Wonderful.
Drive it for 20 years
and it still seems new. - Right.
Then there are Indian cars.
Junk in just a year.
And the roads are full of potholes.
Uncle, this country...
only God can help.
It is ruined. This country
has gone into the potholes.
I had applied for a telephone
eight years back.
No phone, No tone,
nor any reply to my application.
Apply, apply no reply.
Uncle, you get a phone in two days
in foreign countries. - Yes.
Here, you don't get gas connection for
two years, let alone phone connection.
You don't get gas to cook.
What will people eat? Air?
Alice! Alice! Where is Stella?
Ask her to get ready.
Are we going to the movies
today, or tomorrow?
Ruined.
Jaundice, flu, eye disease, stomach
disorders and all diseases are here.
The government tells people
to stay alert and get vaccinated.
And..
Boil water before drinking.
How do you boil water?
There is no cooking gas.
The British era was fantastic.
Now you see India time,
Mumbai is now a slum.
Why just Mumbai,
entire India is one big slum.
I hope we could
go to a foreign country.
Stella is here.
Sorry, Albert.
- It's okay.
We will make it at
least till intermission.
Okay, uncle. Bye. - Bye.
- Take care. Don't get drunk.
Bye.
-Bye Stella.
Take care of the potholes, Albert.
Dominic.
Careful. Be Alert.
It's merch, it's merch!
It's a matter of stomach. Got that?
It's a matter of stomach. - Okay, boss.
Seth Dharam Singh Gokuldas
is hanging out here with us?
He belongs to the same caste
as we do. - Which is that, boss?
Both thieves.
What are you doing?
- I'm reading.
Reading? Do you know what happens?
- Yes, boss.
Tell me.
"I will read(study) for years.
When I get the degree, it would just rot!"
Even if you get a job,
- Blood will boil, you will swat away.
You will work,
continue working.
And what will you get?
- Nothing. - Nothing at all.
Soon after you will die.
Learn from the street.
Learn from the gutters.
..wrongdoings, riots and thefts.
Audacity.
- Learn thoroughly.
Bullying, Bloodshed,
Slitting the throat.
Without a knife.
There's only one thing right.
Right now, right here.
It was a good movie. Nice.
It was a laugh riot.
My stomach hurts laughing. Robert.
He acts so well.
- I didn't like it.
Why don't you take me
to a different movie?
All the movies are similar.
Boy sees girl.
They fall in love. They sing a song.
Some melodrama and
then they get married.
Yeah, that all is fine, but this movie
had great music.
Good. Good music.
Like Goan folk song.
- Right.
In movies, a Goan or Christian is always
shown singing, eating and drinking.
Why?
Doesn't he have any problems?
Does God give him everything?
You are stupid.
This is all just timepass.
People come out and forget it.
Do you really think people
forget what they see in a movie?
Have you seen kids in our locality?
Every kid remembers
the dialogues of 'Sholay'.
Why not?
- 'Hey Sambha! How many were they?'
'What about you, Kalia?'
Listen, let me tell you something.
And it's the truth.
What else is their in our country?
Movies make
millions of people happy.
They forget their sorrows.
They don't want to cry there too.
What's wrong with the car?
What is it?
Has your car broken down?
Do you want us to give it a push?
- No, no, no need.
Hey, please step back a bit.
-Do you have enough petrol sir?
Let me work.
- Have we stopped you?
What a car..
-hey you, hey you.
He's bullying us.
- It's a shiny car.
It's a rocket.
Must be at least 200,000.
It's Rs. 500,000. - How can a car
worth Rs. 500,000 break down?
Gundya, let's go.
- Sir, is this your car?
We have a train to catch.
Joan! - Yes?
-What is today's latest news?
Latest news?
The government is going to make
another small car for the people.
Is this latest news?
Okay, listen to this.
Floods in Bihar leaves
millions homeless.
The minister watched those places
from a helicopter.
Did he get down or stayed up there?
He got down in Patna.
Where else could he get down?
Joan, has Albert
come out of the bathroom?
It is Sunday. He'll be
in the bathroom for two hours.
He will take a bath. Set his hair.
And then he will come out.
Arvind Desai.
Stella...
Why don't you understand?
I'll deal with it.
Stella!
Stella, Stella, Stella, Stella...
Here I come.
Let's keep this here.
They had one last vase.
Thank you. - Doesn't it look good
on your table?
It looks really good!
It would get imitated soon.
- Really? - India...
Thank you, Arvind.
- Okay.
It is made of polyester, right?
Fantastic.
Isn't it great?
- It's very good.
In this country you don't even get
anything good. everything cheap and bad.
You bought this vase
from Singapore, right?
I bought it in Singapore.
But it is from Paris.
what a country.
Mr. D'costa, women work shoulder
to shoulder with men over there.
In fact, they are better than men.
It's wrong. It's absolutely wrong.
People are very dishonest
when it comes to women.
Let me give you an example, uncle.
They show glitter of money
to Christian girls.
Lure her. Trap her. They have fun
with her and also give her promotion.
When it comes to marriage,
they go back to one of theirs.
Everyone isn't bad. Some are good,
some are bad. - Shut up.
You're just a kid.
You won't understand.
It's a matter of pride.
- Albert, please.
Why do you feel hurt
hearing the truth?
Christian girls got educated,
and went to work, so then they are bad.
People look down upon them.
I'm not lying.
In big factories, offices,
it was our girls who were
first to start working there.
Isn't that a great thing?
Now, every other girl wears
shades, jeans and pants.
Who started this fashion
of shades, jeans and pants?
Not everyone says that.
Listen, I.. - Why do you think
everyone is the same? - Shut up!
It's a matter of pride.
- Albert Pinto.
Very profound.
Albert, you aren't aware that
your ideas are very philosophical.
Why not? I always say the right thing.
Very good.
Albert, the minority bill
is in news these days.
what's your opinion?
Mino.. Minority bill?
- Yes. - Yes, it is..
What is that?
What kind of bill is that?
It's about Christians.
I guess you don't know about it.
This vase must be expensive.
It's also very tough.
Have a look.
It's solid.
- Yes.
Unbreakable.
- Yes?
Unbreakable?
Shall I try?
It broke.
Is Vivek here?
No, he has gone out.
What do you want?
I am Vivek's friend. He asked me
to deliver his car. I brought it.
Oh, come in.
Have a seat.
So, you are Vivek's friend?
He comes to me
to get his car repaired.
So, it's your garage?
Garage is Vishwaas Sahab's.
I am a mechanic there.
I'm the chief mechanic.
Pass me that purse.
How much is the bill?
Here you are.
It's for you.
- No. No, ma'am. Take it back.
Vivek asked me to give.
Thank you.
Here are the keys.
Give it to Ramu outside.
Two plates of 'mutton'.
Two plates of 'Raita'.
Two 'Mutter Paneer'.
And some 'Paratha'.
How many 'Parathas', sir?
Pappu, will you have 'Paratha'?
- Yes, dad.
Okay. Four 'Parathas'.
- Four 'Parathas'.
Sir, we have
the best 'Malai Kofta'.
You may add that too.
And one Campa Cola.
No, Thumbs up.
- One Thumbs up.
Pappu, son sit properly.
Anything else, sir?
Poppadam, salad?
Yes, bring that too.
- What are you doing?
Why did you throw sauce on him?
- Pappu, I had told you..
..to behave while in a restaurant.
Pappu, this is bad manners.
It's okay. He's just a kid.
It's all right.
All right. This time we are together.
All right?
Okay. We take your leave.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
- Bye.
Okay.
Why do you worry?
Whatever will happen, let it happen.
Albert, I think
there's a loose contact.
I'll fix it.
- Yes, you are an expert.
Mr. Braganza, I want to ask you
something personal.
My girlfriend Stella.
- Yes.
I quarrel with her every day.
I don't know why.
Well, I do make mistakes,
but so does she.
Mr. Braganza, will these
quarrels stop if we get married?
Albert, concentrate on your work.
First, earn a lot of money.
Buy a flat, car and television.
Think about marriage after that.
- What about the quarrels?
Take her out to the movies.
Go out with her.
She will be happy
and the problem will be solved.
You're right.
Mr. Braganza, do you think the
textile workers would go on a strike??
Albert, I don't waste time
thinking about these things.
Let me tell you a secret.
I am successful because
I concentrate on my work.
You are very talented. Just like me.
Keep working hard and
you'll be very successful.
Don't waste your time
on these things.
Strikes are done by goons
and gangsters.
Strikes..
politics.. everything is nonsense.
Fucking strike, politics
nonsense.
All of it is nonsense.
This is the work of goons.
Father shouldn't
get into these things.
Mama, why don't you explain to him?
He is 50 years old now.
Why does he tangled unnecessarily
into these things?
He should take care of the house.
Has anyone got benefited
by doing strikes?
Father should understand this.
Now, look at Stella..
Mama, how many times
have I told her..
..not to talk to the
mechanics in the garage.
But she doesn't listen to me.
You don't know that
you talk to them nicely..
..but they misunderstand you.
Do you know anything?
Anything about their house?
Mama, they wouldn't have
spoken to any (woman) other than..
...their sisters or mothers.
She comes to the garage
and says hello to them with a smile.
But Albert, is there..
- Mama, I told her thousand times.
She doesn't listen to me.
She'll talk to them with a smile.
They will think that
you are that kind of a girl.
Do we always have to fight?
Stella it's nothing like that.
- Arre, who wants to fight?
I just try to explain
some things to you.
Hopefully
you will get at least something.
Look Albert..
- One minute, mama.
Will you feel good that they will
think of you as that kind of a girl?
I am that kind of a girl na?
You show me the way.
You are always right
and I am always wrong.
Stella..
- It is all my fault.
Wear sari, don't wear a skirt..
Yes..
- Laugh/don't laugh..
Talk to this one,
don't talk to that one.
The people you roam
around with are nice.
The people I talk to are bad.
Why shouldn't I talk to those mechanics?
I like them.
-really
And whatever I like..
you surely won't like that.
Stella, it's nothing like that..
it is just that he..
Even Arvind?
hmmmm?
Albert, I'm leaving.
Albert, she is a nice girl.
Why do you fight?
I was not fighting..
- Then what?
I try to explain to her.
Then go and get her back.
I won't go.
Mama..
Dominic is in jail.
What?
He was caught while stealing.
Pinto.. Dominic Pinto.
Pinto...
Who is Pinot?
You came?
My brother has come to meet me.
Didn't you feel ashamed?
Look Dominic, I..
- Do you have a cigarette?
Look I..
I thought something for you..
When you get out of here..
..then I can get you
admitted in the techno school.
Back to school?
In Technical school.
If you can learn some work, some trade..
- Work, trade..
Look Dominic,
don't make fun of what I am saying.
I am telling you,
if you want to do some work..
..if you want to learn some trade..
I have learnt what I had to learn.
There's only one thing left now.
- What?
I won't spare Bhimiya.
Look you.. you..
you forget Bhimiya. For god's sake.
You'll get into even more trouble.
Here we are worried about
arranging your bail..
Oh my, my family members are
so worried about me?
We all are with you.
If you want to work..
I promise you, I can get you a job.
Time for all that is over
for that now.
Thanks for trying.
Do you have some money?
Take this.
Albert, do you know?
There are three worlds here..
..one is yours, one is mine,
and the third is jail world.
You came here,
thanks for that.
Dominic, listen..
I.. Dominic, listen.
Dominic? Dominic?
Hey Dominic! Dominic!
Come here.
Shall I order for tea?
- Yes.
Today, laborers of cloth
mills have gone on a strike.
This strike is not going to stop.
All the laborers have come together
in the Lalbaugh ground in revolution.
They heard their leaders.
All the workers took an oath
today that they will not go back to work
..until their demands are fulfilled.
'Everyone should be thrown out.'
'Each and everyone
should be thrown out.'
'Scoundrels, traitors.
Throw everyone out.'
When they die of hunger,
they'll know what unemployment means.
There's unemployment in the
country, right? I have a solution.
Fire each and everyone.
Hire new people.
Thousands are unemployed;
anyone can be hired.
These strikers will then
know that work is like god.
They go on a strike
on every little thing.
Work is shut,
city is shut.
Since emergency rule has gone away,
they are doing as they please.
They are ruining the country.
Do you know?
Do you know how much the country
is suffering because of strike?
Millions, billions..
Just see my case.. we lost
such a big order.. from Germany.
This country needs foreign currency.
Foreign exchange.
The union leaders make them
dance like animals.
and they also just dance the dance.
Each of them will be thrown,
only then they'll know.
They don't even believe in god.
Atheist assholes!
Fucking bastards...
Shaving kit.
Is it necessary to shave?
The one's on strike
should look clean.
Why?
He shouldn't look like
as if he has lost.
hmmmm
Did I lose? I? Me?
Did I lose?
I will explain it to him.
Stay quiet now. He is coming.
Vinay, give me a matchbox.
- I don't have it.
Give me a matchbox.
- I don't have it. I told you na.
Tell me, what do you feel?
See Bhimiya,
there shouldn't be any problem.
Brother, there won't be any problem.
The mill owner supports me.
No one can harm us in any way.
Moreover, we are not doing this alone.
There are more fellows with us.
Who?
-Kaliya is there.
Then Chandra.
- Yes.
And the one who stays
in Dongri.. Kania.. - Okay.
They all are doing the same job.
We are not to let more
than 2-3 labourers gather.
If they gather, hit them.
Is there money?
- You'll get lots of money.
You'll get a lots of money.
You listen to me.
Believe me. I'm telling you.
Okay, if I get the money,
and the owner is with us..
..then okay.
- I'm telling the same since then.
Let's do it.
- Yes, let's do it then.
Let's go.
Okay, so we have reached your home..
I brought you comfortably, right?
Thank you.
- Arre, just wait for a minute.
Is our relationship limited
only to work?
Arvind, it is too late.
I shall leave.
Look, there's no one around.
Can't we even talk?
Talk about what?
About us. Look Stella,
I want us both to be friends.
Look, right now, neither
I am in the office nor your boss.
I must ask for a little time,
nothing else.
I want us both to be friends.
You know what I mean? Good friends.
Sometimes in the evenings,
we can go out or something.
Yes.
Don't worry.
Albert will not get to know.
hmmmm
You slapped me?
You bloody bitch! Get out!
Don't come to work from tomorrow.
Do you really believe
that you fired me?
Bitch..
These days, our luck is very bad.
Dominic's brother is coming.
Is her coming here?
Hi.
Bhimya, I was looking for you only.
- So you found me.
Tell me,
why were you looking for me?
Actually... Dominic...
will be released
in a couple of days now.
He.. I want to tell you..
look Bhimiya..
..that guy is a bit hot headed.
- Yes.
But he is a kid.
Please don't fight with him..
- Why will I fight with him?
No, my mother is very worried that
when he.. - Look, look..
When Dominic gets released,
you explain to him.
If he messes with me..
- No, he won't do.. he won't.
But he is also just a kid,
If he tells you something..
- Look, pal.
I understand everything.
If he is a kid,
tell him to sit on his mother's lap..
..and drink milk. Get it?
Now, fuck off.
Go, go.. - Yes, go..
- Trying to tell us..
Why are you pushing me?
- Is it?
Brother, I told you simply leave..
why are you irritating me?
I already have problems.
- Don't push me.
Just leave na.
What do I tell him?
You won't go?
- Go, go.
He says, take care of Dominic.
- Idiot.
Forget it..
Idiot went away.
You apologize to Arvind
and attend the office.
He is a nice guy. He will agree.
No, I won't go.
You won't go?
Why not?
What will you eat?
We need money to run the house.
Do you understand or not?
Do you know why I
had a fight with Arvind?
I don't care about that.
You go for work.
He wants to romance with me.
He wants to trap me.
He thinks, that since I am his secretary,
he owns me
You tell me.
Should I apologize to him?
If you say, I will go.
It is possible that
he might not do it again.
You are misunderstanding him.
I know what he did.
What did he do? I'll tell Albert right
now. He will teach him a lesson.
No.. don't tell Albert.
-But why not?
Albert..
even he doesn't understand me.
Don't you like him?
I like him..
- Then go and please talk to him.
No, Albert will have to come to me.
I am tired.
It runs.. car too..
his and mine too.
"It runs..
car too.. his and mine too."
"If it runs, it is light..
but the car is heavy."
"This is a car worth 5 lakhs."
"A pauper will ride in it.
- What are you saying?"
"On a weighing machine keep this on
one side and on the other, your house."
"If your wife is inside the house,
then even she's sold."
"This is a car worth 5 lakhs."
"Wish this car belonged to me."
"I would've had children and wife."
"It is nothing about me,
but their night would be theirs."
"Why are you crying? Hit the hammer."
"This is a car worth 5 lakhs."
"I don't know what the problem is.
A palace is standing above the house."
"I don't know what the problem is."
"A palace is standing
above the house."
"Uncle is dying of hunger and
the rich man's warehouse is full."
"Tell me if anyone knows."
"What the problem is?"
"You, you, you, you!
May be even he doesn't know."
"What the problem is?"
"This is a car worth 5 lakhs."
"It runs..
car too.. his and mine too."
"If it runs, it is light..
but the car is heavy."
"This is a car worth 5 lakhs."
Dominic, finally today
I am able to meet you.
I am of course a priest,
but am your friend too.
I want to help you. Do you agree?
I will help you, but I need your help.
My help?
Yes, your help
so that I can help you.
Can we meet once a week?
Oh! What's the matter?
What happened?
Nothing, my shirt tore.
How?
Goons.. they had come
to call off the strike.
Good evening, Father.
- Good evening.
How are you?
-I am alright, but are you hurt?
He is of course hurt.
I will get hot water for you.
No need.. this has just began..
For now, I have just been slapped
and threatened.
We'll get to see
much worse ahead.
Father, can you help my father?
What can I do? This is bloodshed.
Who will explain to these heartless?
Who will stop this rioting?
What can we do when everyone
has become each other's enemy?
There's hatred everywhere.
There's nothing like love and peace.
What can anyone do?
We can fight.
No. No one has benefited
by fighting. Never.
My father was thrashed yesterday.
Not very badly,
but he was humiliated.
He is really hurt.
My father never harmed anyone,
but even so, why did this happen to him?
Goons thrashed him.
What do the goons
have to do with strike?
Albert, do you remember
I had told you..
..that the result of
a challenge is fighting?
Do you remember?
- Yes.
Look, now you are very stressed.
When you have cooled down,
we'll talk about this.
Sir.. my father is
a very kind-hearted man.
He is a very simple man.
He's never harmed anyone.
He only demanded his rights.
If anyone demands rights,
do they have to humiliated?
You are telling the same thing again.
See, has anyone got
anything with a strike?
You don't get it?
Do you?
This is a serious issue.
This is a very complex matter.
One day when you are calmer,
we will surely talk about it, okay?
Okay?
- But.. sir..
For now, you should
go home and take rest.
And yes, convince your father
not to get entangled in strike and all.
Only goons and hoodlums do this.
Got it?
I shall leave.
Help us!
Help us, give us bread
for the ones in trouble.
Help us!
Give us roti, give us roti.
Yes.. we are here from Bharat News.
To ask our labour comrades
about the strike.
We have to ask few
questions about the strike.
Our strike is going on..
it is absolutely going on!
To break the strike, the owners
are sending goons and hoodlums.
The owner cannot break the
strike by sending goons and hoodlums.
Apart from bonus,
what else are your demands?
Sir, bonus is a very old debate.
Since four years.
Government announced to give 8% bonus.
Forget 8%,
owner is not ready to give even 4%.
Seth (Owner) says the
company is running in loss.
It is a lie.
Absolute lie.
Whatever we say and whatever you listen,
will it get published in the paper?
Yes, absolutely.
What will you publish? Nothing.
The mill is owned by a seth,
newspaper of another seth.
What will they publish?
Why will they publish?
Bring me some food.
Shall we move from here?
What?
- Shall we move?
There is free place there,
if you say, we'll go and sit there.
Shut up, drunkard.
You brought food from home?
- Yes.
Will you have?
I will eat vada pao.
- It is your wish.
Albert, come on,
your customer is here.
Tell him that 15 more minutes
for the lunch break.
Come on, pal. He is your old customer.
Tell him that I will
have food and come.
Okay.. why should I care?
You'll be in loss.
Hey, come on,
Can't you see he is eating.
-Go away.
Strange.
You've reformed.
Stella..
Stella, I'm sorry.
Actually, that day..
I'm sorry.
Stella, I'm sorry.
Stella, will you marry me?
Daddy..
- Yes.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
In a month or two,
you'll be in Canada.
Did you keep the other papers ready?
Do it today itself.
Post them in the Canadian
embassy tomorrow.
Yeah, I will do all that.
Seems like my thing is sorted.
Look, until your visa doesn't come,
don't tell anyone.
No, no.
- Keep it to yourself.
And yes,
when will you call Alice there?
As soon as I get a job,
Alice will be in Canada.
I don't want to go to Canada.
You don't want to go?
Do you want to rot here?
Are you out of your mind?
Does our people get
any respect in India?
Nobody cares about us.
People are illiterates here..
useless.. good for nothing.
Wherever you go-
there are fights and quarrels.
This place is not ours.
Johnny is right.
India has gone to the shits.
Canada.. now that's a place.
Every person
has first class flat,
car, TV, fridge,
food and drinks..
Everything is A class.
It is a Christian country.
We have some respect there.
We'll know only after we go there.
This is Akashvani Bombay.
Now, you will hear news
from Madhukar Pandey.
The elections of the Colaba district
Panchayat (Village council)
will be held after 2 months.
The governor of Andhra Pradesh,
inaugurated the Filmcity in Hyderabad.
Today is the 15th day of
the cloth mills strike in Bombay.
There has been no resolution
in the talks between
..the labour union
and the owners association.
A spokesperson of the owner's
association told us that..
.. there are batches of laborers
who are now returning to work.
He even said that there are chances of
the strike being called off in few days.
It is a lie.. everything is lie.
What did he say-the spokesperson
at the mill.. he is lying.
He is lying to break our resolve.
Albert..
Until today I didn't tell you
why I am on strike.
It's okay papa..
- I will tell you.. I will tell you.
I have worked for 28 years on
those mill machines.
The noise of the machine
is internalised in my head.
For 28 years I worked
my ass off.
Even when living became
difficult, I stayed silent.
I don't know why I stayed silent.
I had to take care of the family.
I had to raise the children.
Maybe that's why I remained
silent and kept working.
What all we went through..
We didn't get to live with respect
still I remained silent.
Who knows,
maybe I was just a coward.
Owners are not ready to fulfill
even our very small demands.
Now after 28 years,
I have raised my voice.
It is after a long time.
Now I am not going to back down.
I don't know what I will
get by doing strike, but..
..one thing I am sure of
is that I have to fight.
This my chest here na,
cotton has got into it.
There is cotton inside.
The doctor told me that I have
got TB, but I still have to work.
My eyes are just filled
with the mill's smoke.
Wherever I see, I can
just see black.
Till I have these hands,
I have the job,
if it gets severed,
there will be no food.
Do you know the value of this hand?
The hands that work on machine
are worth only Rs. 2000. Rs. 2000.
This is my house.
Everything I have is here.
Eating, sleeping, everything
is here only.
Wherever you see here there's garbage.
Do human beings live like this?
Excuse me,
what is your name?
Ramchander Babbar.
- Where are you from?
Satara. Why?
I was looking for someone.
- Who?
Mohammad Yusuf, Uttar Pradesh.
Ram Singh, Rajasthan.
Ram Sawant, Maharashtra.
Gangaram Chiste, Andhra Pradesh.
Manohar More, Kolhapur.
Bala Unni, Kerala.
Raja Bindeshwari Singh,
Madhya Pradesh.
Venu Gopal, Tamil Nadu.
Rao Bhau Pawar, Maharashtra.
Lakhan Pal, Uttar Pradesh.
Radheshyam Tiwari, Bihar.
Francis Fernandes, Goa.
My name is Albert Pinto.
25th day of strike by the
laborers of Mumbai textile mill.
More than 65 mills are shut.
Chair of the
Bombay millowners association,
Seth Chandumal Podar..
..has opined about the
strike in an interview.
Our country is the biggest sufferer
because of this strike.
The government has incurred
a loss of more than 6 crores.
And at such time, when our country..
- Bloody liar.
..is in dire need
of foreign currency.
We need bread.
- Call it off.
Talk about the countries where
the labor can't go on a strike.
There's so much of
production and happiness.
There should be similar
laws here too.
Then why don't you go there?
- Progress of country..
Why are you dying here?
- Albert!
Who is responsible for the strike?
The leaders of the trade union.
This has become their profession.
We were considering
labourers demands.
We were soon going to decide.
It takes two years to consider?
Hey,
The result... strike.
Ours... country's... labourers...
everyone's loss.
See what all is getting
effected by the strike.
Small scale industries that
are linked to textile mills..
..they are closed down.
Laborers are sitting idle there.
- I see.
He is talking about the laborers now..
Hey, please remain silent.
We have come to see the picture.
You see.. you see.. everyone see it.
Make a fool out of yourself.
Brothers, he is lying.
Shut up.
- What happened to him?
Do you know how much
wage does a mill laborer earn?
Rs. 800.
- All lies!
Hey, shut up.
After working hard for 20 years, do you
know how much a laborer gets? Rs. 800.
Shut up.
- You, shut up.
Hey, enough now. Stay quiet.
- Go out.
Hey, enough is enough.
I think you don't even know
that the laborers who are on strike..
..are taking the help of goons and
stopping the people who want to work.
What nonsense?
Will you stay quiet or not..
- They have hired goons..
How many times should I tell you,
not to allow such people.
I'm telling you, there's still time.
If the labourer leaders accept
their fault.
and call off the strike
..then we will surely
consider laborers demands.
We are not enemies of
the laborers like these leaders.
Laborers are our friends.
We are partners in progress.
What makes Albert Pinto angry?